

HAITHAM ALI GALAHOM



♠ Al Qanayat, Zagazig, Egypt 📞 +201015825755 🗳 haitham_glahom@hotmail.com

A result driven and self-motivated finance professionals with Fifteen years' experience in hospitality financial operation with international hospitality companies, seeking a challenging position with a leading organization to apply accrued skills in making tangible contributions to improve operations and impact the profitability of the business.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Commerce (Accounting)

Sep 1998 - May 2003

Zagazig University, Egypt

LANGUAGES

Arabic Native
English Fluent
French Beginner

WORK EXPERIENCE

Director of Finance Oct 2018 - Sep 2020

Four Points by Sheraton Setif, Setif - Algeria

Hotel Overview

- 191 rooms Four-Star business hotel located in the heart of the city of Setif connected to a mixed-use project consisting of a shopping mall, commercial tower and conference center.
- Dining services include an All-day dining restaurant, Specialty Restaurant, Lounge and Room Service.
- 7 meetings and events rooms with total surface of 1300 square meters.
- Fitness center and outdoor swimming pool.

Task force Deputy Director of Finance

Oct 2017 - Sep 2018

Marriott International - Multiple Properties, Algeria

Hotels Overview

- Sheraton Annaba Hotel, 201 rooms Five-Star business hotel with dinning service include 2 Restaurants, 2 Bars and lounges and meetings facilities of 6 meeting rooms with total space of 1370 square meters and other facilities include fitness center and outdoor pool.
- Constantine Marriott Hotel, 180 rooms Five-Star business hotel with dinning service include 3 Restaurants, 2 Bars and lounges and meetings facilities of 6 meeting rooms with total space of 1845 square meters and other facilities include fitness center, Spa, outdoor pool and indoor swimming pool.
- Protea Hotel by Marriott Constantine, 72 rooms Four-Star selected services business hotel with Dining
 facilities include restaurant and Bar and meetings facility of 3 meeting rooms can accommodate events from
 10 to 100 guests and 2 message rooms Spa.

Deputy Director of Finance

Jan 2016 - Oct 2017

The Westin Soma Bay Golf Resort & Spa, Hurghada - Egypt

Hotel Overview

- 166 rooms Five-Star resort located in Soma Bay peninsula on Egypt's Red Sea coast, the hotel is connected to 18-hole golf course and Spa & Thalasso center.
- Indoor and outdoor dining services include 3 Restaurants, Lobby lounge, British style pub and in room dining.
- Meeting and wedding facilities, Fitness Studio, Tennis & Squash Courts, Swimming pool and Private beach.

Chief Accountant / Senior Accountant

Oct 2013 - Jan 2016

W Doha Hotel and Residences, Doha - Qatar

Hotel Overview

- 442 guest rooms and suites Five-Star luxury lifestyle hotel located in west bay of Doha.
- Dining facilities include 3 Michelin stars and international restaurants, 2 Lounges, W Café and in room

dining.

7 Meetings and events rooms with total space of 1750 Square meters.

Income Auditor Aug 2012 - Jul 2013

Coral Boutique Hotel Baghdad, Baghdad - Iraq

Hotel Overview

- 80 rooms 4-Star boutique hotel Located in the heart of Baghdad in Jadriya area 2 km from Green Zone.
- Dining Services include an All-day dining restaurant, Garden café and lounge
- 50 square meters meeting room

Accounts Payable / Night Auditor

Sep 2007 - Aug 2012

Sheraton Soma Bay Resort, Hurghada - Egypt

Hotel Overview

- 306 rooms Five-Star resort located in Soma Bay peninsula on Egypt's Red Sea coast.
- Indoor and outdoor dining services include 3 Restaurants, 4 bars and lounges, and in-room dining.
- 4 Meetings and events rooms and outdoor weddings facilities.
- Fitness center, Spa, Tennis & Squash Courts, Swimming pool, Private beach and water sports center.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Opening Four Points by Sheraton Setif introducing an international hospitality standard in the city.
- In 2019 Peoplesoft Stabilization score card, the hotel was ranked #1 out of 250 Marriott properties in MEA.
- Savings of USD 180K in expenses resulted in +200% flow through to budget in 2019. Financial figures
- Managed the Westin Soma Bay Limited cash flow during the tourism unrest in Egypt.
- Succeed to improve Westin Soma YOY control effectiveness percentage by 5pts and achieve green rating in 2017 Regional DOF peer review.
- Improve Westin Soma Bay forecast accuracy and achieve total revenue MEPE improvement by 10pts YOY in 2017.
- Assisted with achieving the yearly budgeted GOP in W Doha Hotel and Residences 2013, 2014 and 2015.
- Assisted with achieving Green rating in Three consecutives regional DOF Peer reviews in W Doha Hotel and Residences.

OTHER TASKS AND RESPONSBILITES

- Engaging in Strategic Planning and Decision Making.
- Anticipating and Delivering on the Needs of Key Stakeholders.
- Developing and Maintaining Financial Goals.
- Managing Projects and Policies.
- Leading and coaching Finance Teams.

REFERENCES

References available on request.